MD Al Shahariar Kobir Shakil

Agargaon, Dhaka, Bangladesh

■ +880 1623023732 ■ mask.shakill@gmail.com 🛅 Linkedin 🕥 Github

Summary

With 1.5 years of experience in Software Development. I have proven my ability to build reusable web front-end components and back-end REST API. I have a strong interest and explore in new technology and committed to creating scalable web solutions.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, HTML/CSS

Development Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Express.js, Django, Tailwind CSS

Database Technologies: SQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase

Developer Tools: VS Code, Postman, Android Stdio, Git/GitHub, Selenium, Cypress, Vercel, Netlify

Work Experience

Full Stack Web Developer — Finixware(Remote)

March 2023 - February 2024

I have worked on several projects under Finixware, including Service Operator and School Finder BD.

School Finder BD

March 2023 - August 2023

- The goal of this project was to develop a platform for locating Bangladesh's top and closest schools.
- Developed front-end using React.js, Tailwind CSS and Redux.
- Developed back-end using Node.js, Express.

Service Operator

November 2023 - February 2024

- The project's objective is to provide a platform that makes it simple to create jobs and links clients and service providers.
- Developed front-end using React.js, Tailwind CSS and Redux.js, daisy UI, flowbite, firebase.
- Developed back-end using Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.

Projects

Functional Todo — February 2023 GitHub Live

The attractively styled Functional my Todo website is a task management tool designed with Tailwind CSS and React. It enables seamless state management by utilizing the Context API, and permanent user data is ensured by local storage integration.

EasyMart Grocery — November 2023 Github Live

EasyMart Grocery is a platform powered by Next.js that revolutionizes online grocery buying. Tailwind CSS is used to ensure seamless navigation. We make sure your shopping experience is both effective and pleasurable by utilizing SEO optimization strategies and leveraging MongoDB for efficient data management. Daisy UI, Flowbite, and Next-Auth authentication are just a few of the features that make EasyMart Grocery a safe and convenient interface for all your grocery needs.

Red Cars — March 2024 Github Ongoing

Red Cars is an smart platform designed to make finding new automobile models and their current costs easier. It provides powerful filtering and search features for easy exploration using Next.js Full-stack, Tailwind CSS, and MongoDB. Red Cars is your go-to automotive buddy for easy and accurate automobile finding and pricing.

My Blog REST API — October 2023 Github

The REST API on myblog website is powered by Node.js and Express.js and easily integrates with MongoDB for effective data management. It provides users with an interactive platform to interact with a variety of content and delve into a broad range of subjects.

Django REST Todo — February 2024 Github

Django REST Todo has been skillfully crafted using the Django Rest Framework and SQLite, offering a meticulously designed REST API tailored for a real-world Todo application. It has provided practical experience in creating reliable back-end systems with contemporary web development frameworks and has been primarily intended for practice purposes.

Education

BSc in Computer Science & Engineering Green University of Bangladesh Dhaka, Bangladesh 2020-2024
Relevant Courses: Structure Programming, Data Structure & Algorithm, Object Oriented Programming, Operating System, Web Programming, Database, Information System Design, Software Engineering & Artificial Intelligence.

Online Courses & Certifications

- Introduction to Javascript (2022) Udemy
- HTML/CSS Basic To Advanced (2020) w3schools
- Full-Stack Web Development (2022) Coursera
- Learn Python Full Course for Beginners (2023) freecodecamp
- Complete Web Development (2022) Programming Hero
- Django REST Framework (2024) Documentation & Youtube
- Typescript for beginners (2023) Documentation & Youtube

Extra-curricular Activities

- Worked as a Dedicated Volunteer at ICPC 20222 Asia Dhaka Regional Organized by Green University.
- Worked as a Dedicated Volunteer at the 4th International Conference of Sustainable Technologies for Industry 2022
 Organized by IEEE Green University of Bangladesh.
- Worked as a volunteer at CSE CARNIVAI 2020 Organized by Green University Computer Club.
- I am passionate about solving problems, and I like taking on challenges on various online platforms to keep improving my coding abilities and algorithmic reasoning. I can maintain my focus and improve my problem-solving skills by tackling a variety of challenges.
- LeetCode
- HackerRank

Languages

• Bengali [Native]

• English [Professional working proficiency]